<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Storytime | ROODAY]]></title>
  <link href="http://ROODAY.com/blog/categories/storytime/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ROODAY.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-11T15:38:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ROODAY.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rudhra Raveendran]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[rudytheninja@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Storytime: The Four Kanyes]]></title>
    <link href="http://ROODAY.com/blog/storytime"/>
    <updated>2014-10-07T21:54:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ROODAY.com/blog/storytime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Prompt:<br/>Kanye West is one of the four Kanye&rsquo;s. The other three being Kanye North, Kanye South, and Kanye East. More commonly known as the Four Kanye&rsquo;s of the Apocalypse.</p><footer><strong>Praetorzic <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/27wfo7/wp_kanye_west_is_one_of_the_four_kanyes_the_other/">http://www.reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/27wfo7/wp_kanye_west_is_one_of_the_four_kanyes_the_other/</a> Original Prompt</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Millenia ago, before the dawn of creation, there was naught but the Void. An endless whirlpool of chaos, where nothing could thrive. After centuries of nullity, four divine beings stepped forth from the Void, and became the keepers of the Unisphere, the plane of existence they created. From that point on, they were known as the Four Kanyes of the Apocalypse, Kanye North, Kanye South, Kanye East, and Kanye West.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Their first act as supreme rulers was to populate their realm with humanity. The seeds of man sprang forth from the same chaos that begot the rulers themselves, and the Unispehere was filled with worlds and life. Within 6000 years, the human species had spread not only throughout their world, but the worlds that spanned their plane, and their existence outshadowed all else. Even more, their brightest scientists discovered an incredible technology, the ability to bend the strings that made up their existence, and open a path to the Universe, a plane hitherto undiscovered by even the Kanyes. With each passing day, they discovered new realms to conquer, and multiplied like bacterium. At first, the Kanyes were pleased with their creation. As a parent felt pride in seeing their child prosper, so too did the divines feel gratification as their greatest experiment now exceeded their greatest hopes.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But humanity could not keep expanding forever. As they continued to ravage everything that they came across, the Kanyes grew nervous of their power. Should the humans continue to grow at such a rate, they would one day overpower the keepers themselves. And this was a future that the Kanyes would prevent at all costs. They devised a plan, one in which they would bring humans to their knees, and reassert their dominance over all creation. And so they sent the most powerful of the four, Kanye West. Before, when the Kanyes were the absolute power of all the Unisphere, the very name Kanye West would make entire civilizations crumble. One look from his shutter shades would cast an entire galaxy into the cold grasp of death. It was a logical assumption that he could bring back humans into the thrall of the keepers. Unfortunately for all life in the universe, they were wrong.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
